

BEKRY MOHAMMED

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

A software developer with excellent programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and python. I posses a very good understanding of databases, frameworks and version control. - I have 12 years of experience in Engineering, teamwork and collaboration with international teams. I am excited to join a dynamic software developer team in the tech sector so that I can advance and make a difference.



bekrye@gmail.com



Germany



🚢 25.12.1984, in Tigray, Ethiopia

- GitHub repository: https://github.com/bkv201/

EDUCATION

April 2023 - Present Diploma in Fullstack Software Development

Code Institute, GmbH Deutschland

Full Stack Software Development

September 2019 - July 2021

MASTER OF SCIENCE in Data Engineering Jacobs University Bremen, Germany

- All aspects of data engineering and ML process, including building ETL pipelines, and preprocessing
- Selected courses: Big Databases and Cloud Services, Machine learning, Data Visualization

October 2004 - July 2008

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Electrical Engineering Jimma University, Ethiopia

-signal processing, computer programming, computer networks, communication engineering

SKILLS

Programming: HTML / CSS / Javascript / Python

OS: Linux / Windows

Database: SQL / MySQL / MongoDB / PostgreSQL

Containerization: Kubernetes / Docker

Version control: Git / Github

Frameworks: Django / jQuery / Bootstrap

Cloud Services and Storage: AWS

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- 1. Aerobics Sport: Interactive site for Gym membership subscription. GitHub https://github.com/bky201/Aerobic-sport Technologies used - HTML, CSS, GitHub, Fontawesome
- 2. Dice Step game: Interactive Game uses random guess to create a path. GitHub https://github.com/bky201/step-game Technologies used - HTML, CSS, Javascript, GitHub, Fontawesome
- 3. Battleship Game: Interactive Game between user and computer. GitHub https://github.com/bky201/battleship-game Technologies used - Python, Heroku, GitHub

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2022 - January 2023

Rider

Gorillas Operation Germany GmbH & Co KG

Bremen, Germany

- Delivery of Goods to customers.
- Product quality and expiry date checking.
- Ware house product organization and storage.

September 2021 – December 2021

Fulfillment Center Associate

Amazon Logistik Achim GmbH, Bremen, Germany

- Inbound dock, products distribution.
- Stowing and storing items inside pods.
- Bar code scanning and product checking

July 2020 – July 2021 Working Student DPD Deutschland GmbH VZ Bremen, Germany

- Inbound dock, products distribution.
- Outbound dock storing items inside container.

September 2017 - July 2019

Electrical Engineer

EDNA MALL HTS PLC Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Performed data analysis and created visualization dashboards.
- Plan and monitor project progress.
- Prepared weekly progress reports

January 2014 – September 2017

Freelancer

China Railway Construction Engineering Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Supervision project execution on site.
- Prepared material request for site execution.
- Tested and Handed over completed projects.

March 2009 – June 2013 Electrical Engineer Alsaad General Contracting Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Installed electrical systems for Automation of Buildings.
- Installed Fire alarm and Voice evacuation systems.
- Tested and Handed over completed networking systems.

CERTIFICATION

- Udemy : Agile Fundamental Including Scrum and Kanban - 2021 (4.5 hours)

- Udemy : Cloud Computing with AWS Amazon Web Services (10 hours)

- Udemy : Docker and Kubernetes The Practical Guide (23.5 hours)

- Udemy : Build React Node AWS MERN Stack Real Estate Marketplace App (19 hours)

- Udemy : The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert! (69 hours)

- Udemy: The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp (65.5 hours)

- Udemy: Web Scraping in Python BeautifulSoup, Selenium and Scrapy 2022 (9 hours)

LANGUAGES

Tigrinya: Native English: Expert

German: Business Fluent

INTEREST

- Playing football: Engaging in the exhilarating sport of football provides an active outlet for physical fitness, teamwork, and the joy of competing.
- Watching movies: The captivating experience of watching movies allows for immersion in different narratives, Emotions and visual storytelling.
- Spending time with friends: Sharing moments and creating cherished memories with friends fosters connections, laughter, and a sense of belonging in a supportive social circle.